<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Ambiguous Implicits - Paul Lysak&#39;s blog about programming</title>
    <link>http://www.aimplicits.com/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Ambiguous Implicits - Paul Lysak&#39;s blog about programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 18:33:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.aimplicits.com/tags/javascript/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript deferreds are almost monads</title>
      <link>http://www.aimplicits.com/posts/2013-01-04-javascript-deferreds-are-almost-monads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 18:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aimplicits.com/posts/2013-01-04-javascript-deferreds-are-almost-monads/</guid>
      <description>When I was learning monad concept from functional programming I suddenly realized that deferred objects avaiable in some JavaScript libraries (for example in Dojo - http://livedocs.dojotoolkit.org/dojo/Deferred) are strikingly similar to monads.
Haskel has the clearest definition of the monads so let&#39;s start from it (don&#39;t get scarried, I&#39;ll explain essentials later):
class Monad m where
(&amp;gt;&amp;gt;=) :: m a -&amp;gt; (a -&amp;gt; m b) -&amp;gt; m b
(&amp;gt;&amp;gt;) :: m a -&amp;gt; m b -&amp;gt; m b</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for JavaScript grid/table component</title>
      <link>http://www.aimplicits.com/posts/2012-12-28-looking-for-javascript-gridtable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 16:43:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aimplicits.com/posts/2012-12-28-looking-for-javascript-gridtable/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was looking for grid/table component in Javascript which is would be open-source, flexible enough and not tied heavily to some large framework. I&#39;d like to share with you some brief notes of that research. I like SlickGrid more so I&#39;ve explored it more. SlickGridhttps://github.com/mleibman/SlickGrid/wikiLicense: MIT PROs: Supports huge datasets via virtual scrolling. Looks like it&#39;s the only grid that supports horizontal virtual scrolling. &amp;nbsp;Supports trees Data provider API - allows model creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency management in JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://www.aimplicits.com/posts/2011-10-25-dependency-management-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 11:57:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aimplicits.com/posts/2011-10-25-dependency-management-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Imagine web-application with lots of JavaScript code and CSS files which depend on each other. Each page needs specific JS and CSS files, but it&#39;s not always easy to say which exactly - pages are constructed from relatively independent parts.
Moreover, some content which needs JS may be loaded asynchronously.
So, I&#39;m goin to make some research about flexible ways of dependency management with JavaScript and blog about it.
RequireJS</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
